Guide to the Edwin and Terry Murray Fanzine Collection, 1948-2019 RL.00925
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Edwin and Terry Murray Fanzine collection
1948-2019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Murray, Edwin [collector]
RL.00925
43 Linear Feet
Edwin L. and Terry A. Murray, brothers residing in Durham, N.C., have been collectors of comic books and other pulp culture for forty years. The Murray Fanzine Collection contains approximately 1150 comic book, science fiction and fantasy fanzines, collected by Edwin and Terry Murray, representing fandom in these genres from the early 1950s to 2019, as well as advertisements for fandom gatherings and conventions. The collection is organized into one series that is loosely separated into two sections: the first, and larger, consists of comic book fanzines ranging from the beginning of comic book fandom in the early 1960s to the retrospective volumes published in the early 2000s. The fanzines include reviews, advertisements and commentary, as well as biographical information on a variety of artists and writers, including Carl Barks, R. Crumb, Will Eisner, Steven King, Jack Kirby and Stan Lee. Though an assortment of superhero and comic strip characters published by DC, Dell and Marvel Comics, among others, are cited, one character in particular, Donald Duck, recieves more attention than the others. The second section consists of a sampling of science fiction and fantasy fanzines (including fantasy fiction) ranging from 1952 to the early 1980s, including information on artists and writers such as Vaughn Bode and Harlon Ellison. Most of the fanzines in the collection were printed independent of large scale publishing techniques, utilizing ditto, mimeograph, hectograph and, later, photocopy, on paper of varying degrees of quality. There are also three additional accessions (2010-0107, 2019-0078, 2019-0103), which have been minimally processed.
1150 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Edwin and Terry Murray Fanzine Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift between 2002 and 2019.
Biographical Note
Edwin L. and Terry A. Murray, brothers residing in Durham, N.C., have been collectors of comic books and other pulp culture for forty years. Edwin published his own fanzines, Vertigo and Trefoil, from the late 1960s through the mid 1980s. He graduated from Duke University in 1972. Edwin was at the center of comics fandom in the 1960s and 1970s. Terry, a science fiction expert, is the author of Science Fiction Magazine Story Index, 1926-1995 (McFarland, 1999).
Collection Overview
The Murray Fanzine Collection contains approximately 1150 comic book, science fiction and fantasy fanzines representing fandom in these genres from the early 1950s to 2019. The collection is organized into one series that is loosely separated into two sections: the first, and larger, consists of comic book fanzines ranging from the beginning of comic book fandom in the early 1960s to the retrospective volumes published in the early 2000s. The second section consists of a sampling of science fiction and fantasy fanzines ranging from 1952 to the early 1980s. Most of the fanzines in the collection were printed independent of large scale publishing techniques, utilizing ditto, mimeograph, hectograph and, later, photocopy, on paper of varying degrees of quality.
Boxes 349-367 contain those fanzines pertaining to comic fandom. The earliest examples represented in the collection date to the early 1960s, just after the very first comic fanzines had appeared, including Alter Ego, which is included here from issue 4, and Comic Art. Other notable titles included in the collection from this era (often referred to as the Golden Age of Comic Fandom) are Masquerader, Rocket's Blast/Comic Collector, Yancy Street Journal, Batmania, Comic Crusader, Gosh Wow! and SPA FON, as well as many others. Several of these issues contain photos and/or contributions from the Murray brothers, who had participated in comics fandom beginning in the mid 1960s. Fanzines dedicated to E.C. comics (such as Squa Tront, and E.C. Fan Journal), comprehensive indexing (such as Jerry Bails Authoritative Index to DC Comics and Guidebook to Comic Fandom, the MLJ Comic Index and The Comic Fan's Guide to Periodical Literature, which indexed early articles relating to comic books), conventions (such as the programs to the 1966 New York ComiCon and the 1968 International Convention of Comic Art, which is autographed by several of the artists in attendance), and amateur comic strips (such as Captain Biljo Comics and The Eye) are also represented from this era. Also included are issues 1-4 of Comics Review, which contain the first published fiction by Stephen King.
The era represented in the largest number is the 1970s, a time when the Murray brothers were very active in fandom, both in publishing as well as collecting. Though most of the issues represented in the collection from this era are single issues, some of the more popular titles, such as Bode' Bulletin, New Fangles, and In The Shadow of the Monolith, are represented in larger numbers. Trefoil and Vertigo, both published by Edwin Murray, are represented in full. As nostalgia became big business in the 1980s, comic books and comic fandom became more marketable. In turn, a much larger percentage of publications dedicated to comic fandom and collecting benefitted from a higher production budget. In addition, the proliferation of the photocopy allowed for a higher production number on a smaller budget. These changes are represented in the collection, from the glossy Disney collectables magazine Storyboard and the Fantaco Chronicles Series, to the photocopied Barks Collector, Duckburg Times, and The Stanley Steamer. Though none of the major fanzines/magazines of the late 1980s and 1990s, such as the Comics Journal, Wizard, and Comic Buyers Guide are represented, several of the retrospective books on Comics Fandom published by Hamster Press are included in the collection.
Boxes 368-372 contain fanzines relating to sci-fi and fantasy fandom, some of which are represented in both sections. Though not as complete a representation of the fandom of these genres as of the comics fandom genre, this section contains several of the top titles, including Don-O-Saur, Tolkien Journal, SF Commentary, Lan's Lantern, and Focal Point. Also included is a 1952 issue of Science Fantasy Bulletin published by Harlan Ellison, which was part of the initial wave of sci-fi fandom that was so influential to the beginnings of comic book fandom. It should also be noted that scattered throughout the collection are fanzines devoted to film, particularly horror and sci-fi films, as well as fliers (including one for the first symposium on Donald Duck held in the Geology department at Duke in 1970) and other assorted ephemera.
There are also three additional accessions (2010-0107, 2019-0078, 2019-0103), which have been minimally processed.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series. The first accession has been virtually rearranged by title in alphabetical order, the physical arrangement is numerical by box number (found to the left of each individual title listed in the finding aid). Three accessions have been added to the collection and are unsorted. We have listed the titles in each box.
Related Material
Edwin and Terry Murray Comic Book Collection.
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Bingham Center Women's Zine Collection.
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Science fiction; Science fiction fans; DC Comics, Inc.; Comic books, strips, etc.; Comic book fans; Biography -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Advertising -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Fan magazines -- Periodicals; Fan magazines -- Reviews; Marvel Comics Group; Fantasy comic books, strips, etc.; Fantasy fiction; Fan magazines -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Dell Publishing Company; Walt Disney Productions; Donald Duck (Comic Strip); Murray, Edwin L. Edwin and Terry Murray Collection of Pulp Culture; Kirby, Jack; Lee, Stan; Murray, Edwin L.; Crumb, R.; Eisner, Will; Ellison, Harlan; King, Steven; Bode, Vaughan; Barks, Carl; Murray, Terry A., 1953-
- Fanzines, 1952-2003, 24 boxes
  - The 007 Collector, 2 (1966) (Box 355)
  - A Fanzine (Devoted to the Work of Walt Disney), Vol. II, 2 (1969) (Box 361)
  - The Acadamy of Comic Book Arts Newsletter, 6-7, 9-12, 14-15, 17, 20-21, 24-29 (1971-1974) (Box 364)
  - Al Williamson: His Work, 1 (1971) (Box 359)
  - All Star Comics Review, 1 (1977) (Box 351)
  - All Stars, 1 (1965) (Box 355)
  - Allen H. Greenfield's: Mom's Apple Pie, Vol. I; Vol. II (1973) (Box 370)
    Scope and Contents note
    Contains Jules Verne Bibliography
  - Alter Ego, 4-11 (1962-1969, 1978) (Box 359)
  - Anomaly, 1-3 (1969-1971) (Box 360)
  - Anomaly, 1 (1973) (Box 372)
  - APA-H, 64 (1978) (Box 371)
  - Aphelion, 2 (1976) (Box 355)
  - The Atlanta Fan, 1 (1975) (Box 355)
  - Atropos, 4 (1977) (Box 371)
  - Authoritative Index to All Star Comics, 1 (1965) (Box 352)
    Published by Jerry Bails
  - Authoritative Index to DC Comics, 1 (1963) (Box 352)
  - Avenging Aardvark's Aerie, 10 (1978) (Box 371)
  - Awry, 1 (1972) (Box 370)
  - Backyard Rocket, 1-4 (1971-1972) (Box 363)
  - Badmouth, 1-3 (1971) (Box 371)
  - The Barks Collector, 7-34 (1978-1986) (Box 361)
  - Batmania (plus Annual), 1-16, 18-23, Annual (1964-1967,1974-1977) (Box 352)
    Annual issue contains letter from Bob Kane
  - Batwing, 1-3 (1965) (Box 356)
  - Beabohema, 18 (1971) (Box 370)
  - Beardmutterings, 1-2 (1971-1972) (Box 370)
  - Beyond the Clock, 24-26 (1980) (Box 352)
  - Bizarre, 1 (1973/1974) (Box 363)
  - Bode' Bulletin, 1-3, 5-8 (1971-1972) (Box 353)
  - Bombshell, 7-10 (1967) (Box 356)
  - Bulletin (of the Fantasy Fans-Comicollectors), 31 (1971) (Box 370)
  - Burger, 1 (1971) (Box 363)
  - Burried Treasure, 1-2 (1986) (Box 365)
  - Burroughs Bulletin, 34 (1974) (Box 370)
  - Capa-Alpha, 105,106 (1973) (Box 350)
  - Captain Biljo Collector's Item Comics for 1967, 1 (1967) (Box 355)
  - Captain Biljo Comics, 1 (1968) (Box 355)
  - Captain Biljo Presents, 1 (1968) (Box 355)
  - The Captain Kentucky Collection, Vol. I (1981) (Box 365)
  - Carolina International, 3-5 (1976) (Box 363)
  - The Cartoonist, 1 (1966) (Box 355)
  - Celestial Shadows, 9-10 (1972) (Box 353)
  - Cinegore, 5-7 (1972-1973) (Box 363)
  - The Classics Handbook, 1 (undated) (Box 349)
  - Collectibles Monthly, 12 (1978) (Box 372)
  - The Collector, 11 (1968) (Box 356)
  - Collector's Guide: The First Heroic Age, 1 (1969) (Box 352)
  - Comic Art, 6-7 (1966-1968) (Box 358)
    Issue 7 contains interview w/ Carl Barks
  - Comic Art Convention, 1970, 1 (1970) (Box 349)
  - The Comic Art Showcase, 1 (1970) (Box 363)
  - Comic Artist, 1-2 (1969) (Box 356)
  - Comic Book, 1 (1966) (Box 356)
  - Comic Comments, 9, 14-15, 17-28 (1966-1971) (Box 355)
  - Comic Contents, 1-2 (1964) (Box 355)
    Issues 1-2 contain first published articles by Edwin Murray (on Hawkman and Doom Patrol)
  - Comic Crusader Story Book, 1 (undated) (Box 365)
  - The Comic Crusader, 3-17 (1968-1974) (Box 365)
    Issues 3 and 7 contain photos of Edwin and Terry Murray at the 1968 Comicon
  - The Comic Fan, 2 (1965) (Box 356)
  - Comic Fandom Monthly, 1-8 (1971-1972) (Box 356)
  - Comic Fandom Reader, 1 (2002) (Box 364)
  - The Comic Fan's Guide to Periodical Literature, 1 (1961) (Box 352)
  - Comic Lore, 1-2 (1967) (Box 356)
  - The Comic World, 2-21 (c.1962-1979) (Box 351)
    Issues 17 and 18 contain articles by Edwin Murray on ACG
  - Comic Zine, 1 (1964) (Box 352)
  - Comicology Fan Review, 1 (1976) (Box 355)
  - Comicon Bonus, 1 (1966) (Box 355)
  - Comics Commentary, 3 (1970) (Box 356)
  - Comics Review, 1-4 (1965) (Box 355)
    Issues 1-4 contain I was a Teenage Grave Robber, first published work by Stephen King
  - Comix Unlimited, 1 (1968) (Box 356)
  - Compass, Vol. III, 4 (1977) (Box 371)
  - Complete Guide to Classics Collectibles, Vol.I (1991) (Box 351)
  - Con Confessions, 5, 7-8 (1975,1977,1986) (Box 350)
  - Concussion, 2, 5 (1967-1968) (Box 356)
  - Constitution of the National Fantasy Fan Federation, 1 (1970) (Box 369)
  - Crashing Waves, 1 (1980) (Box 363)
  - Critique, 1-2 (1968) (Box 355)
  - Cullowhee Comments, 1-5 (1974) (Box 363)
  - Cum Bloatus, 1 (1972) (Box 371)
  - Daily Discard, The, 4 (1974) (Box 353)
  - Dangling Conversation, 4 (undated) (Box 356)
  - Dark Continent, 2 (1970) (Box 356)
  - Deadspawn, 1 (1975) (Box 362)
  - Delap's F&SF Review, 3 (1975) (Box 370)
  - Denfen Droppings, 2 (undated) (Box 372)
  - Destiny of Science Fiction, 1 (1975) (Box 371)
  - Detroit Triple Fan Fair Guide, 1 (1969) (Box 356)
  - Devlin's Review, 1-2 (1975-1977) (Box 369)
  - Diaspar, 16 (1974) (Box 369)
  - Diehard, 8 (1976) (Box 371)
  - Discombobulated Daily, Vol. I, 1-2 (1974) (Box 355)
  - Discon II Progress Report, 1-5 (1974) (Box 349)
  - Discon II Program Book, 1 (1974) (Box 349)
  - Disneydom, 1 (1969) (Box 361)
  - Diversity, 19 (undated) (Box 354)
  - DJ's College Book & Newsletter, 1 (1980) (Box 363)
  - Donald Duck Story Reprints By Carl Barks, (undated) (Box 365)
  - Don-O-Saur, 28-37, 39-51 (1974-1978) (Box 368)
  - The Duckburg Times, 8-16,19-21 (1980-1982, 1983-1985) (Box 361)
  - The Early Barks, Vol. I and II (undated) (Box 362)
  - The EC Fan Addict, 2-3 (undated) (Box 355)
    Early EC fanzine from the 1960s
  - EC Fan Journal, 6 (undated) (Box 355)
    Early EC fanzine from the 1950s
  - ECCO, 1-6 (1967-1969) (Box 363)
  - Energumen, 13 (1972) (Box 370)
  - Ered Nimrais, 2-7,12 (1976-1978) (Box 354)
  - ERG Quarterly, 46 (1974) (Box 371)
  - Eternity Road, 3 (1975) (Box 371)
  - Extra Heavy News, 1-15 (1977-1979) (Box 365)
  - Extravaganza, 1 (1972) (Box 363)
  - The Eye, 1-2 (1965, 1969) (Box 355)
  - Famous Films and Funnies: Kazanda, 1 (1970) (Box 363)
  - Fan Informer FFCG Newsletter, Vol. IV, 31 (1974) (Box 356)
  - The Fanarchist Flyer, 1 (undated) (Box 370)
  - The Fanarchist, (undated) (Box 370)
  - Fandom Annual, 3 (undated) (Box 364)
    Contains early Uncle Scrooge checklist compiled by Don Rosa
  - Fandom's Agent, 1-5,7-8 (1968) (Box 356)
  - Fandom's Finest Comics, Vol.I-II (1997-1998) (Box 364)
  - Fantaco's Chronicles Series, 2-5, Annual 1 (1982-1983) (Box 365)
  - Fantagor 1, 1 (1970) (Box 359)
  - The Fantaphile Journal, 1-3 (1967-1968) (Box 363)
  - Fantasy Illustrated, 1-7 (1963-1967) (Box 358)
    Becomes Graphic Story Magazine
  - Fantasy Mongers, 1 (1979) (Box 371)
  - Fiawol, 1-3 (1972) (Box 368)
  - Fighting Hero Comics, 9-10 (1964) (Box 355)
  - File 770, 1 (1978) (Box 369)
  - First Fandom Fanzine, 1 (1977) (Box 371)
  - Flash Comics Special, 1 (1967) (Box 355)
  - Flight of the Goovey Bird, (undated) (Box 370)
  - Flip, 3-4 (1969) (Box 363)
  - Focal Point, Vol. II, 2-3, 6-25,27-30; Vol. III, 1-5 (1970-1971) (Box 368)
  - Focus On: George Perez, 1 (1985) (Box 365)
  - Focus On: Jack Cole, 1 (1986) (Box 365)
  - [FD6] The Four Door Grape, 5 (1970) (Box 363)
  - Funnyworld, 10-22 (1968-1980) (Box 360)
  - Gallery, 1 (1969) (Box 356)
  - The Gamesletter, 64 (1973) (Box 371)
  - Gegenschein, 1, 14, 18-19 (1974-1975) (Box 371)
  - Genoor, 3 (1967) (Box 371)
  - George, 1-10 (1971-1972) (Box 364)
  - Giant Labors of Love, 1 (2000) (Box 364)
  - Glx Sptzl GLAAH!, 1 (1977) (Box 351)
  - Gobs, 27 (1983) (Box 362)
  - Godless, 3-7, 9-10, 12-13 (1973-1975) (Box 354)
  - Godless, 11 (1974) (Box 363)
  - The Golden Age of Comic Fandom, 1 (1999) (Box 364)
  - Golden Age Super Hero Index, 1 (1968) (Box 352)
  - The Golden Age, 1-3 (1965-1966,1968) (Box 353)
  - Gosh Wow!, 1-3 (1967-1969) (Box 352)
  - Gotham Gazette, Vol. I, 1-4 (1965) (Box 355)
  - Granfalloon, 15-16 (1972) (Box 370)
  - Graphic Art Review, 1-2 (1973) (Box 354)
  - Graphic Showcase, 1-2 (1967) (Box 356)
  - Graphic Story Bookshop Newsletter, 1 (1973) (Box 356)
  - Graphic Story Magazine, 8-16 (1967-1973) (Box 358)
    Previously titled Fantasy Illustrated
  - Greater Days of Westerns, The, 1 (1974) (Box 349)
    Contains correspondence between Edwin Murray and Gary Brown
  - Green Gomrath, 7 (1973) (Box 353)
  - The Guide To September, 1 (1975) (Box 363)
  - Guidebook to Comics Fandom, 1 (1965) (Box 355)
  - Guying Gyre, 5-8,10 (1976-1977) (Box 371)
  - Half a Decade of Demented Dwarf Press Publications, 1 (1973) (Box 354)
  - Hannes Bok Illustration Index, 1 (1970) (Box 352)
  - Hello Again, 1 (1973) (Box 371)
  - Hembeck, 1-2,4-7 (1979-1983) (Box 365)
  - Hero Hobby, 23 (1970) (Box 363)
  - Heroes, 1-3 (1982-1983) (Box 362)
  - Heroes Aren't Hard To Find Catalog, 1-11 (1982-1983) (Box 362)
  - Heroes' Hangout, 2-3 (1964) (Box 353)
  - Heroes Illustrated, 2-3 (1966, 1968) (Box 353)
  - Hollywood Electern, 1-2,11 (1992-1994) (Box 359)
  - Hop Slop, 1 (undated) (Box 363)
  - Horizons, 127,140 (1971, 1974) (Box 369)
  - Howard Keltner's Index to Golden Age Comic Books, 1 (1976) (Box 352)
  - Huitloxopetl, 7 (undated) (Box 362)
  - IBID, 18,20-21,26-30,32,34,37-39,42-44,55-56,60-66,81,83-90 (1970-1973, 1976-1977, 1986-1987) (Box 350)
  - Illustrated Comic Collector's Handbook, Vol. I-IV (1966-1969) (Box 352)
  - Impossible Adventures, 25 (undated) (Box 363)
  - In the Shadow of the Monolith, 1-66 (1970-1977) (Box 366)
  - International Convention of Comic Art, 1968, 1 (1968) (Box 349)
    Program autographed by artists
  - It Comes in the Mail, 1-7,9-28 (1972-1977) (Box 353)
  - Jellybeans, 1,3 (1977, 1978) (Box 350)
  - Jinnia Clan Journal, Vol. I, 9-12; Vol. II, 1-3, 11; Vol. III, 3; Winter 77; Spring 78 (1974-1978) (Box 354)
  - John Stanley: A Humble Life, 1 (1996) (Box 359)
  - Journal of the V.F.B.M., 1 (1969) (Box 355)
  - Kosmic City Capers, 3-4 (1974) (Box 370)
  - Lan's Lantern, 9-15 (1979-1984) (Box 368)
  - Lan's Lantern, 6-8 (1977-1979) (Box 371)
  - Les Spinge, 31 (1974) (Box 372)
  - Lettered Observations & Cosmic Comments, 4 (1981) (Box 355)
  - The Liberated Quark, 6 (1978) (Box 353)
  - Listing of Dell Special Series Comic Books, A, 1 (1968) (Box 352)
    Contains early list of Dell Four Color Comics by Maggie and Don Thompson
  - Locomotive, 3 (1974) (Box 363)
  - Locomotive, 1 (1973) (Box 370)
  - Log of the Starship Aniara, 4 (1976) (Box 355)
  - Luna, 37 (1972) (Box 370)
  - Mad World of Marveldom/Marvel Mirror, 1,3-7 (1967) (Box 356)
  - Madame Frog's Catalog of the Occult, 1 (1972) (Box 363)
  - Make Room! Make Room!, 1 (1976) (Box 353)
  - Marvel Main, 1 (1968) (Box 356)
  - Masquerader, 1-6 (1962-1964) (Box 365)
    Contains early (Fall 1962) article about Spiderman
  - Maybe: Worlds of Fan Fiction, 6, 13-14, 17, 21, 24, 26, 34, 36-40, 42-43, 45, 48 (1970-1976) (Box 354)
  - Mechta, 1 (1973) (Box 370)
  - Media Five Magazine, 5-6 (1974) (Box 371)
  - Melotoons, 1 (1972) (Box 356)
  - Memphis Film & Nostalgia Festival 1975, 1 (1975) (Box 349)
  - Memphis Film & Nostalgia Festival 1976, 1 (1976) (Box 349)
  - Metro Comic Art Convention, 1970, 1 (1970) (Box 349)
  - Microscopium, 1,4-5,7 (1973-1976) (Box 355)
  - Mid Americon Progress Report & Program, 2-4 (1976) (Box 349)
  - The Midgard Journal, 6 (1974) (Box 371)
  - Miskatonic, 16 (1976) (Box 355)
  - MLJ Comic Index, 1 (1969) (Box 352)
  - MLP Bookservice Catalogue, (undated) (Box 372)
  - Mumble Gutter, 6 (1980) (Box 353)
  - The Mutant, 2-5 (1975-1976) (Box 355)
  - Myth Print, Vol. VI, 1-6; Vol. VII, 1 (1972-1973) (Box 369)
  - Mythlore, Vol. I, 4; Vol. II, 2-4 (1969-1972) (Box 370)
  - National Fantasy Fan, June and August issues (1970) (Box 369)
  - National Fantasy Fan Federation Roster, 1 (1970) (Box 369)
  - The New Newport News, 4-5 (1968, 1970) (Box 353)
  - New Nickle Library, 5, 7, 12-13, 17, 19-23 (undated) (Box 356)
  - New York Comicon, 1966, 1 (1966) (Box 349)
  - Newfangles, 19-54 (1969-1972) (Box 355)
  - Newspaper clippings with publicity for Durham Mini-cons (Box 367)
  - Nexus, 4-6 (1971-1972) (Box 370)
  - Niekas, 18,20 (1967-1968) (Box 369)
  - Nifty Adventure Funnies, 1 (1972) (Box 363)
  - Nightwinds: The Voice of the Guild, 1 (1979) (Box 370)
  - nosfan23, Vol. VI, 1 (1976) (Box 355)
  - Nova 1, 1 (1972) (Box 349)
  - Nozdrovia, 1 (1968) (Box 370)
  - Nucleus, 3-8 (undated) (Box 363)
  - Obecalp, 1.5,2,24-25 (1971-1972,1976-1977) (Box 350)
  - Oblio, 0,1,3,5,9,22,25,27-30,34-38,46-48 (1971-1973,1975-1978,1986-1987) (Box 350)
  - ODD Magazine, 20 (1969) (Box 356)
  - Om Markstein Skcom Stu, 14 (1971) (Box 354)
  - Omniverse, 1-2 (1977, 1979) (Box 351)
  - The One-Shot Barks (undated) (Box 362)
  - The Oriflamme, 2-3 (1970) (Box 363)
  - The Oriflamme, 1 (1970) (Box 372)
  - Outer Limits, 1 (1975) (Box 355)
  - Outre, 4 (1966) (Box 355)
  - Outworlds, 21/22 (1975) (Box 371)
  - Pablo Lennis, 2 (undated) (Box 371)
  - Panelologist (plus supplement), Vol. I, 1-8; Vol. II, 1 (1967,1971) (Box 351)
  - Paradox, 6 (1965) (Box 372)
    Contains early fanzine bibliography.
  - Paragon, 3 (1970) (Box 356)
  - The Passing Parade, 3-4 (1972) (Box 370)
  - Pathless Trails, 2 (1977) (Box 355)
  - Perigee, 1 (1973) (Box 363)
  - Phantasmagoria, 1 (1971) (Box 359)
  - Phosphene, 5-6 (1977) (Box 372)
  - Photron, 9 (1976) (Box 355)
  - Pinball Lizard, 5 (1979) (Box 353)
  - Pit, 1 (1971) (Box 363)
  - Poof, 1 (undated) (Box 355)
  - Popilania, 1 (1980) (Box 363)
  - Prehensile, 6 (1972) (Box 370)
  - Purple Prose 5, Vol. II, 1 (1996) (Box 367)
  - Radix, Prelude, 1, 2 (1976-1976) (Box 354)
  - Rally, 33,35,38,40-41 (1977-1978) (Box 354)
  - Rally, 39 (1978) (Box 371)
  - Rare Comix Brochure, (undated) (Box 363)
  - Ray-Gun, 3 (1968) (Box 356)
  - Reason and Knowledge, 2 (1969) (Box 363)
  - Rebel Yells, Vol. II, 2 (undated) (Box 362)
  - Rhubarb, 2-3 (1981) (Box 371)
  - Riverside Quarterly Advertisement (Box 368)
  - Rocket's Blast Special, 1,3-6 (1964-1965) (Box 359)
  - The Rocket's Blast/Comicollector Annual, 1 (1965) (Box 359)
  - San Diego's West Coast Comic Convention, 1972, 1 (1972) (Box 349)
  - Savage Gentleman, 4 (undated) (Box 363)
  - Schwartz Index, 1 (1965) (Box 353)
  - Science Fantasy Bulletin, 11 (1952) (Box 369)
    Published by Harlan Ellison
  - Science Fiction Times-Chronicle, Vol. XIX, 101 (1973) (Box 362)
  - Science Fiction Times-Chronicle, Vol. XIX, 101 (1973) (Box 370)
  - Sense of Wonder, 1-12 (1967-1972) (Box 364)
  - SF Commentary, 20,28-29,34,38,40 (1971-1974) (Box 370)
  - SFPA 67- A Sort of 1/2-Vast Con Report, 1 (1975) (Box 353)
  - Shockway, Vol. II, 6 (1977) (Box 363)
  - Shot Scott Rap Sheet, 8,10,13,21,23-25,27-28,30,32 (1976-1977,1980-1983) (Box 349)
    Contains early Paul Chadwick Art
  - Shroud, Vol. II, 1 (1966) (Box 356)
  - Skiffy Bag, 1 (1979) (Box 353)
  - Skiffy Thyme, 1 (1980) (Box 353)
  - Skug, 3-4 (1978-1981) (Box 371)
  - Slam Bang, 2-5 (1964-1965) (Box 358)
  - Snickersnee, Vol. Flip; Vol. Zip (1974) (Box 369)
  - So It Goze, 1,3-15 (1973-1974,1977) (Box 353)
  - Son of Grafan, 5 (1971) (Box 370)
  - Son of the WFSA Journal, 173-174 (1975) (Box 355)
  - Sootli, 1 (1976) (Box 371)
  - South of the Moon, Vol. I, 1-3 (1975-1976) (Box 353)
  - Southern Fandom Confederation Bulletin, 2-17,19-23,25,27-28 (1971-1983) (Box 362)
  - Southern Fandom Confederation Roster, 1-5,8 (1972-1978) (Box 362)
  - Southern Fandom Handbook for Southern Fandom Confederation, (1974, 1977, 1980) (Box 362)
  - SPA FON, 2-4 (1966-1967,1969) (Box 352)
  - Spockanalia, 3 (1968) (Box 370)
  - Squa Tront, 1-9 (1967-1983) (Box 359)
  - Stanley, 19 (1978) (Box 371)
  - The Stanley Steamer, 1-60 (1982-1992) (Box 359)
  - Star Date 1982-1983: The Barks Collector Annual No. 1, 1 (1983) (Box 360)
  - Starling, 23 (1972) (Box 370)
  - Starworlds, 1 (1971) (Box 370)
  - Sterenko Portfolio 1, 1 (1970) (Box 358)
  - Storyboard, Vol. I, 3-6; Vol. II, 1,4-6; Vol. III, 1-2 (1988-1990) (Box 360)